<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.mrshell.PiLauncher</id>
  <icon type="remote">https://mrshellad.github.io/PiLauncher-Flatpak/icon.png</icon>
  <name>PiLauncher</name>
  
  <summary>Minecraft Launcher for Gamepad</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh_CN">专为手柄设计的 Minecraft 启动器</summary>

  <developer id="com.mrshell">
    <name>MrShell</name>
  </developer>

  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>

  <description>
    <p xml:lang="zh_CN">PiLauncher 是一款为游戏手柄和掌机量身定制的 Minecraft 启动器。它拥有为主机式体验优化的全屏用户界面，让你可以轻松地使用手柄管理、配置和运行你的 Minecraft 游戏实例。</p>
    <p>PiLauncher is a Minecraft launcher tailored for gamepads and handheld consoles. It features a full-screen, console-like user interface optimized for controller inputs, allowing you to easily manage and launch your Minecraft instances.</p>
    <ul>
      <li xml:lang="zh_CN">完全支持手柄操作，提供沉浸式大屏体验。</li>
      <li>Full gamepad support for an immersive large-screen experience.</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh_CN">自动识别和配置手柄相关模组。</li>
      <li>Automatic detection and configuration of gamepad-related mods.</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh_CN">极简且现代化的实例和模组管理。</li>
      <li>Minimalist and modern instance and mod management.</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://pi.nav4ai.net/screenshots/01.webp</image>
      <caption>Home</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://pi.nav4ai.net/screenshots/02.webp</image>
      <caption>Download</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://pi.nav4ai.net/screenshots/03.webp</image>
      <caption>Setting</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.mrshell.PiLauncher.desktop</launchable>

  <categories>
    <category>Game</category>
  </categories>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.1.43" date="2026-06-19">
      <description>
        <p xml:lang="zh_CN">全新引入首次启动设置向导，并优化了模组的元数据处理和信息同步体验。</p>
        <ul xml:lang="zh_CN">
          <li>[新功能] 全新引入首次启动设置向导（Setup Wizard），自动引导新用户进行核心游戏路径选择、Java 运行环境检测与绑定、Steam 库导入以及用户协议确认，大幅简化首次配置流程。</li>
          <li>[优化] 优化模组元数据处理和交互，提升了模组信息的识别与多平台元数据同步稳定性。</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Introduced an initial Setup Wizard for first-time startup, and improved mod metadata handling and synchronization experience.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>[New] Introduced an initial Setup Wizard for first-time startup to guide users through selecting game directory, auto-detecting/binding Java, integrating Steam libraries, and confirming user agreements.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Refined mod metadata processing and UI interaction, improving the stability of metadata identification and synchronization.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.42" date="2026-06-15">
      <description>
        <p xml:lang="zh_CN">新增资源下载页浏览历史返回功能，优化翻页加载稳定性与模组信息保留机制，并改善多处交互体验。</p>
        <ul xml:lang="zh_CN">
          <li>[新功能] 资源下载页支持浏览历史返回：点击作者名搜索后，可通过返回按钮或鼠标侧键回到之前的搜索结果和滚动位置。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 翻页加载失败时会自动重试，多次失败后提供"手动继续加载"按钮，不再一翻页失败就丢失已有结果。</li>
          <li>[优化] 翻页加载时底部显示骨架屏动画，替代之前的旋转图标，视觉体验更流畅。</li>
          <li>[优化] 更新模组版本后，模组的名称、图标、描述等信息不再丢失，升级模组更省心。</li>
          <li>[优化] 手动重命名模组文件后，启动器能自动识别并保留原有的模组信息记录。</li>
          <li>[优化] 刷新模组列表时，已加载的图标和更新状态不再闪烁消失，列表更稳定。</li>
          <li>[优化] 模组详情中切换到 CurseForge 源时，若未配置 API Key 会给出明确提示。</li>
          <li>[优化] "重新识别全部模组"操作前会自动保存当前的元数据平台设置，避免设置丢失。</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Added browsing history navigation in the download pages, improved load-more reliability with auto-retry, and enhanced mod metadata retention across updates.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>[New] Added browsing history back-navigation in the download pages: after clicking an author name to search, you can go back to your previous search results and scroll position via a back button or mouse side button.</li>
          <li>[New] Load-more now automatically retries on failure, and shows a manual "Retry" button after repeated failures instead of discarding existing results.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Replaced the spinning loader with smooth skeleton animations when loading more results for a better visual experience.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Mod metadata (name, icon, description) is now preserved when updating to a new version, so you won't lose track of your mods after upgrading.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Manually renamed mod files are now automatically recognized and matched to their original metadata records.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Refreshing the mod list no longer causes loaded icons and update status indicators to flicker or disappear.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] A clear message is now shown in Mod Details when CurseForge is selected but no API key is configured.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] The "Re-identify All Mods" action now auto-saves your current metadata platform settings before running.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.41" date="2026-06-10">
      <description>
        <p xml:lang="zh_CN">新增已删除实例的友好提示，优化第三方登录与皮肤站的开启逻辑，并进一步提升了局域网联机安全性与设置页面的流畅度。</p>
        <ul xml:lang="zh_CN">
          <li>[新功能] 新增已选中实例被删除时的友好提示与重新选择引导，避免因实例缺失导致启动异常。</li>
          <li>[优化] 优化设置页面加载性能，系统字体在后台异步预加载，使页面打开更加流畅。</li>
          <li>[优化] 优化局域网在线信任设备的安全校验机制，提升局域网安全性。</li>
          <li>[优化] 优化资源下载页面的分类切换逻辑，切换标签时自动重置版本与加载器筛选。</li>
          <li>[优化] 优化实例选择弹窗的滚动条显示效果。</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Added friendly reminders for deleted instances, optimized the activation logic for third-party logins/skin stations, and improved LAN multiplayer security and Settings page responsiveness.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>[New] Added friendly notifications and re-selection guidance when a selected game instance is deleted to prevent startup errors.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Improved Settings page loading by preloading system fonts asynchronously in the background, making the UI smoother to open.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Enhanced the security verification mechanism for trusted devices on the local network to improve LAN multiplayer security.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Refined tab-switching logic in the download center, automatically resetting version and loader filters when changing tabs.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Enhanced the scrollbar experience within the instance selection modal.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.40" date="2026-06-07">
      <description>
        <p xml:lang="zh_CN">新增光影资源收藏支持，深度优化 Windows 平台下的文件链接创建逻辑，并美化了资源下载与新闻页面的动画效果及加载体验。</p>
        <ul xml:lang="zh_CN">
          <li>[新功能] 资源下载支持直接收藏光影包，方便管理和快速下载常用光影。</li>
          <li>[优化] 重构 Windows 文件链接创建逻辑，优先采用目录联接（Junction）和硬链接，不再需要管理员权限，并彻底解决 Minecraft 与 Java 无法识别文件符号链接的兼容性问题。</li>
          <li>[优化] 优化资源下载页面，引入平滑的页面过渡动画与全新的骨架屏加载效果，消除界面加载闪烁。</li>
          <li>[优化] 美化新闻列表页面，引入流畅的卡片载入动画与渐变投影，优化无障碍加载体验。</li>
          <li>[优化] 改进 3D 皮肤预览器的渲染效率与性能表现，减少运行卡顿。</li>
          <li>[优化] 调整下载默认配置，默认关闭分块下载以提升资源下载的兼容性与稳定性。</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Added support for favoriting shader resources, optimized file linking logic on Windows, and enhanced animations and loading transitions for the download and news pages.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>[New] Added support for favoriting shader packs directly in the download section.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Refactored Windows file linking logic to prioritize directory junctions and hard links, eliminating the need for admin rights and solving compatibility issues where Java/Minecraft failed to recognize file symlinks.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Optimized the resource download page with smooth layout transition animations and a new shimmer skeleton loader.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Refreshed the news page with smooth card entry animations, gradient shadow styling, and improved loading experience.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Optimized 3D skin viewer rendering efficiency to deliver a smoother visual performance.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Disabled chunked downloads by default to improve general download compatibility and stability.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="0.1.39" date="2026-06-05">
      <description>
        <p xml:lang="zh_CN">新增游戏库与按键配置的云端同步、手柄键位管理以及多实例下载，并全面优化了列表性能、无障碍体验与暗黑模式样式。</p>
        <ul xml:lang="zh_CN">
          <li>[新功能] 支持游戏库文件与手柄快捷键配置的 WebDAV 双向云同步，并具备冲突解决机制。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 新增手柄按键映射与快捷键管理功能，支持配置默认键位。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 优化资源下载逻辑，支持一键将资源下载并关联至多个游戏实例。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 增加本地游戏实例自动识别与游戏版本检测功能。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 新增 Steve 和 Sunny 等经典角色形象头像资源。</li>
          <li>[优化] 引入虚拟列表技术重构关联管理面板，大幅提升大量资源项下的列表滚动性能。</li>
          <li>[优化] 适配并美化了下载详情界面和资源卡片的暗黑模式样式。</li>
          <li>[优化] 全面优化了手柄与键盘在各界面中的焦点导航与无障碍交互体验。</li>
          <li>[优化] 优化了赞助者皮肤渲染与皇冠标识展示，并在游戏库页面右键菜单中增加资源类型标注。</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Added cloud sync for library files and keymaps, custom keymap management, multi-instance resource downloads, and optimized list performance, accessibility, and dark mode.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>[New] Added WebDAV bi-directional cloud synchronization for library files and keymaps with conflict resolution.</li>
          <li>[New] Added custom gamepad keymap and shortcut management with default bindings.</li>
          <li>[New] Enhanced download logic to support downloading and linking resources to multiple game instances simultaneously.</li>
          <li>[New] Added automatic local instance detection and game version handling.</li>
          <li>[New] Added new character avatar assets (Steve and Sunny).</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Integrated virtual lists in the manage linkage view to significantly improve scrolling performance for large collections.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Improved dark mode styles for resource cards and download detail components.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Overhauled gamepad and keyboard focus navigation across various views for a better accessibility experience.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Enhanced donor skin rendering and crown displays, and added resource type labels to context menus in the library.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="0.1.38" date="2026-05-31">
      <description>
        <p xml:lang="zh_CN">新增版本更新日志弹窗与翻译 API 配置，优化更新提示与项目图标动画效果。</p>
        <ul xml:lang="zh_CN">
          <li>[新功能] 新增更新日志弹窗，支持在应用内查看版本更新记录并进行多语言翻译。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 设置中新增翻译 API 配置，支持自定义翻译服务。</li>
          <li>[优化] 引入平滑动画效果，提升项目图标的视觉动态体验并优化资源网格的响应式布局。</li>
          <li>[优化] 改进更新提示功能，优化各组件的提示界面与交互表现。</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Added a version changelog modal and translation API configuration, and optimized update reminders and project icon animations.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>[New] Added a version changelog modal to view update details in-app with translation support.</li>
          <li>[New] Added translation API configuration and integration in settings.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Integrated animations for project icons and enhanced the responsiveness of the resource grid.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Enhanced update reminder functionality and adjusted related user interfaces.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="0.1.37" date="2026-05-29">
      <description>
        <p xml:lang="zh_CN">集成游戏启动前检查与修复机制，深度重构模组元数据管理，优化手柄焦点与无障碍交互体验。</p>
        <ul xml:lang="zh_CN">
          <li>[新功能] 新增游戏启动前检查功能，支持自动补全与验证运行库，并提供运行时修复引导对话框。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 支持游戏退出时自动备份世界存档，保障玩家存档安全。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 模组管理支持收藏与置顶功能，并引入全新的模组元数据设置和删除确认弹窗。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 引入全新的 OreCheckbox 基础组件，并整合至实例选择、资源卡片与网格视图中。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 新增基础 UI 组件库展示与交互预览页面，方便开发与组件调试。</li>
          <li>[优化] 重构模组详情、资源包、材质包、光影及存档管理面板，全面支持列表快照功能与性能指标展示。</li>
          <li>[优化] 针对手柄操作大幅优化了新闻、微软账户侧边栏、下载管理器以及通用组件（卡片、下拉菜单等）的焦点跳转逻辑与空间导航无障碍体验。</li>
          <li>[优化] 强化国际化多语言本地化支持，优化各级界面的英文等长文本布局溢出表现。</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Integrated pre-launch verification &amp; repair checks, overhauled mod metadata management, and optimized gamepad focus and accessibility.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>[New] Added pre-launch compatibility checks with automatic runtime verification/downloading and an interactive runtime repair dialog.</li>
          <li>[New] Added automatic world save backups on game exit to safeguard player progress.</li>
          <li>[New] Added support for favoriting/pinning mods, alongside new mod metadata settings and deletion confirmation modals.</li>
          <li>[New] Introduced the OreCheckbox primitive component, integrated into instance selection and resource displays.</li>
          <li>[New] Added an interactive UI component showcase page for previewing and testing primitive elements.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Refactored Mod, Resource Pack, Save, and Shader panels with snapshot tools and improved metadata layouts.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Overhauled focus navigation and accessibility for gamepads in News, Account Sidebar, Download Manager, and core primitives (dropdowns, buttons).</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Enhanced internationalization support (i18n) and layouts to prevent text overflows.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="0.1.36" date="2026-05-21">
      <description>
        <p xml:lang="zh_CN">新增 WebDAV 同步与增强皮肤管理功能</p>
        <ul xml:lang="zh_CN">
          <li>[新功能] 引入全新的 WebDAV 自动同步功能，支持跨设备同步启动器设置与皮肤资源。</li>
          <li>[优化] 升级“衣柜”功能，全面增强了皮肤管理体验和模型渲染效果。</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Added WebDAV sync and enhanced skin management</p>
        <ul>
          <li>[New] Introduced WebDAV auto-sync to effortlessly synchronize launcher settings and skin assets across devices.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Upgraded the Wardrobe feature with an enhanced skin management experience and improved 3D rendering.</li>

        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="0.1.35" date="2026-05-15">
      <description>
        <p xml:lang="zh_CN">新增资源库功能，并改进资源浏览与掌机设置体验。</p>
        <ul xml:lang="zh_CN">
          <li>新增资源库，可收藏、整理和查看常用资源。</li>
          <li>新增模组集跟踪，管理一组常用模组更方便。</li>
          <li>下载页分类标签支持本地化，查找资源更直观。</li>
          <li>优化资源列表和资源库的滚动体验，浏览更顺手。</li>
          <li>新增掌机设置页，集中管理性能配置和 Steam Deck 按键布局。</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Added the Library and improved browsing and handheld settings.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added a Library for saving, organizing, and viewing frequently used resources.</li>
          <li>Added mod set tracking to make groups of favorite mods easier to manage.</li>
          <li>Localized download category labels so resources are easier to find.</li>
          <li>Improved scrolling in resource lists and the Library for smoother browsing.</li>
          <li>Added a Handheld settings page for performance options and Steam Deck key layout controls.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="0.1.34" date="2026-05-10">
      <description>
        <p xml:lang="zh_CN">重构模组详情界面，优化性能并修复全屏模式开关失效问题</p>
        <ul xml:lang="zh_CN">
          <li>[重构] 深度重构模组详情弹窗，适配小屏幕响应式布局，操作按钮移至底部操作区。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 模组版本列表支持跨平台自动匹配，解决切换来源后找不到版本的问题。</li>
          <li>[修复] 彻底修复全屏模式开关失效的 Bug，现在启动器设置可以强制覆盖游戏的内部全屏状态。</li>
          <li>[优化] 大幅提升模组列表滚动流畅度，通过全新的图标预加载与缓冲机制解决了图标闪烁问题。</li>
          <li>[优化] 改进了删除确认弹窗的排版，提升触控与手柄交互体验。</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Overhauled Mod Detail UI, Performance Improvements, and Fullscreen Fix</p>
        <ul>
          <li>[Refactor] Deeply refactored the Mod Detail modal with a responsive layout for small screens and unified action buttons in the footer.</li>
          <li>[New] Added cross-platform project ID matching for mod versions, ensuring history displays correctly when switching sources.</li>
          <li>[Fix] Resolved a critical bug where the fullscreen toggle was ignored; the launcher now correctly enforces your preferred window mode.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Significant performance boost for mod list scrolling, eliminating icon flickering via an improved pre-loading and buffering system.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Improved layout of deletion confirmation dialogs for better touch and gamepad interaction.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
      </release>

    <release version="0.1.33" date="2026-05-08">
      <description>
        <p xml:lang="zh_CN">集成 Authlib-injector 支持与披风自定义功能</p>
        <ul xml:lang="zh_CN">
          <li>[新功能] 集成 Authlib-injector 支持，支持第三方登录（如小皮肤、LittleSkin 等）。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 支持自定义披风 URL，让你的角色外观更加个性化。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 新增客户端安装遥测功能，并提供相关的隐私设置开关。</li>
          <li>[优化] 重构了身份验证服务与登录界面，显著提升系统稳定性。</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Integrated Authlib-injector Support and Custom Cape Support</p>
        <ul>
          <li>[New] Added Authlib-injector support for third-party authentication services like LittleSkin.</li>
          <li>[New] Added support for custom cape URLs.</li>
          <li>[New] Introduced client installation telemetry with a dedicated privacy toggle in settings.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Restructured authentication services and overhauled the login UI for better stability.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>

  </releases>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <supports>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>pointing</control>
    <control>touch</control>
    <control>gamepad</control>
  </supports>

  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/MrShellad/pilauncher</url>
  <url type="homepage">https://pil.nav4ai.net</url>



</component>
