<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.mrshell.PiLauncher</id>
  <icon type="remote">https://mrshellad.github.io/PiLauncher-Flatpak/icon.png</icon>
  <name>PiLauncher</name>
  
  <summary>Minecraft Launcher for Gamepad</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh_CN">专为手柄设计的 Minecraft 启动器</summary>

  <developer id="com.mrshell">
    <name>MrShell</name>
  </developer>

  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>

  <description>
    <p xml:lang="zh_CN">PiLauncher 是一款为游戏手柄和掌机量身定制的 Minecraft 启动器。它拥有为主机式体验优化的全屏用户界面，让你可以轻松地使用手柄管理、配置和运行你的 Minecraft 游戏实例。</p>
    <p>PiLauncher is a Minecraft launcher tailored for gamepads and handheld consoles. It features a full-screen, console-like user interface optimized for controller inputs, allowing you to easily manage and launch your Minecraft instances.</p>
    <ul>
      <li xml:lang="zh_CN">完全支持手柄操作，提供沉浸式大屏体验。</li>
      <li>Full gamepad support for an immersive large-screen experience.</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh_CN">自动识别和配置手柄相关模组。</li>
      <li>Automatic detection and configuration of gamepad-related mods.</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh_CN">极简且现代化的实例和模组管理。</li>
      <li>Minimalist and modern instance and mod management.</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://pi.nav4ai.net/screenshots/01.webp</image>
      <caption>Home</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://pi.nav4ai.net/screenshots/02.webp</image>
      <caption>Download</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://pi.nav4ai.net/screenshots/03.webp</image>
      <caption>Setting</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.mrshell.PiLauncher.desktop</launchable>

  <categories>
    <category>Game</category>
  </categories>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.1.38" date="2026-05-31">
      <description>
        <p xml:lang="zh_CN">新增版本更新日志弹窗与翻译 API 配置，优化更新提示与项目图标动画效果。</p>
        <ul xml:lang="zh_CN">
          <li>[新功能] 新增更新日志弹窗，支持在应用内查看版本更新记录并进行多语言翻译。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 设置中新增翻译 API 配置，支持自定义翻译服务。</li>
          <li>[优化] 引入平滑动画效果，提升项目图标的视觉动态体验并优化资源网格的响应式布局。</li>
          <li>[优化] 改进更新提示功能，优化各组件的提示界面与交互表现。</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Added a version changelog modal and translation API configuration, and optimized update reminders and project icon animations.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>[New] Added a version changelog modal to view update details in-app with translation support.</li>
          <li>[New] Added translation API configuration and integration in settings.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Integrated animations for project icons and enhanced the responsiveness of the resource grid.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Enhanced update reminder functionality and adjusted related user interfaces.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="0.1.37" date="2026-05-29">
      <description>
        <p xml:lang="zh_CN">集成游戏启动前检查与修复机制，深度重构模组元数据管理，优化手柄焦点与无障碍交互体验。</p>
        <ul xml:lang="zh_CN">
          <li>[新功能] 新增游戏启动前检查功能，支持自动补全与验证运行库，并提供运行时修复引导对话框。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 支持游戏退出时自动备份世界存档，保障玩家存档安全。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 模组管理支持收藏与置顶功能，并引入全新的模组元数据设置和删除确认弹窗。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 引入全新的 OreCheckbox 基础组件，并整合至实例选择、资源卡片与网格视图中。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 新增基础 UI 组件库展示与交互预览页面，方便开发与组件调试。</li>
          <li>[优化] 重构模组详情、资源包、材质包、光影及存档管理面板，全面支持列表快照功能与性能指标展示。</li>
          <li>[优化] 针对手柄操作大幅优化了新闻、微软账户侧边栏、下载管理器以及通用组件（卡片、下拉菜单等）的焦点跳转逻辑与空间导航无障碍体验。</li>
          <li>[优化] 强化国际化多语言本地化支持，优化各级界面的英文等长文本布局溢出表现。</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Integrated pre-launch verification &amp; repair checks, overhauled mod metadata management, and optimized gamepad focus and accessibility.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>[New] Added pre-launch compatibility checks with automatic runtime verification/downloading and an interactive runtime repair dialog.</li>
          <li>[New] Added automatic world save backups on game exit to safeguard player progress.</li>
          <li>[New] Added support for favoriting/pinning mods, alongside new mod metadata settings and deletion confirmation modals.</li>
          <li>[New] Introduced the OreCheckbox primitive component, integrated into instance selection and resource displays.</li>
          <li>[New] Added an interactive UI component showcase page for previewing and testing primitive elements.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Refactored Mod, Resource Pack, Save, and Shader panels with snapshot tools and improved metadata layouts.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Overhauled focus navigation and accessibility for gamepads in News, Account Sidebar, Download Manager, and core primitives (dropdowns, buttons).</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Enhanced internationalization support (i18n) and layouts to prevent text overflows.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="0.1.36" date="2026-05-21">
      <description>
        <p xml:lang="zh_CN">新增 WebDAV 同步与增强皮肤管理功能</p>
        <ul xml:lang="zh_CN">
          <li>[新功能] 引入全新的 WebDAV 自动同步功能，支持跨设备同步启动器设置与皮肤资源。</li>
          <li>[优化] 升级“衣柜”功能，全面增强了皮肤管理体验和模型渲染效果。</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Added WebDAV sync and enhanced skin management</p>
        <ul>
          <li>[New] Introduced WebDAV auto-sync to effortlessly synchronize launcher settings and skin assets across devices.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Upgraded the Wardrobe feature with an enhanced skin management experience and improved 3D rendering.</li>

        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="0.1.35" date="2026-05-15">
      <description>
        <p xml:lang="zh_CN">新增资源库功能，并改进资源浏览与掌机设置体验。</p>
        <ul xml:lang="zh_CN">
          <li>新增资源库，可收藏、整理和查看常用资源。</li>
          <li>新增模组集跟踪，管理一组常用模组更方便。</li>
          <li>下载页分类标签支持本地化，查找资源更直观。</li>
          <li>优化资源列表和资源库的滚动体验，浏览更顺手。</li>
          <li>新增掌机设置页，集中管理性能配置和 Steam Deck 按键布局。</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Added the Library and improved browsing and handheld settings.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added a Library for saving, organizing, and viewing frequently used resources.</li>
          <li>Added mod set tracking to make groups of favorite mods easier to manage.</li>
          <li>Localized download category labels so resources are easier to find.</li>
          <li>Improved scrolling in resource lists and the Library for smoother browsing.</li>
          <li>Added a Handheld settings page for performance options and Steam Deck key layout controls.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="0.1.34" date="2026-05-10">
      <description>
        <p xml:lang="zh_CN">重构模组详情界面，优化性能并修复全屏模式开关失效问题</p>
        <ul xml:lang="zh_CN">
          <li>[重构] 深度重构模组详情弹窗，适配小屏幕响应式布局，操作按钮移至底部操作区。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 模组版本列表支持跨平台自动匹配，解决切换来源后找不到版本的问题。</li>
          <li>[修复] 彻底修复全屏模式开关失效的 Bug，现在启动器设置可以强制覆盖游戏的内部全屏状态。</li>
          <li>[优化] 大幅提升模组列表滚动流畅度，通过全新的图标预加载与缓冲机制解决了图标闪烁问题。</li>
          <li>[优化] 改进了删除确认弹窗的排版，提升触控与手柄交互体验。</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Overhauled Mod Detail UI, Performance Improvements, and Fullscreen Fix</p>
        <ul>
          <li>[Refactor] Deeply refactored the Mod Detail modal with a responsive layout for small screens and unified action buttons in the footer.</li>
          <li>[New] Added cross-platform project ID matching for mod versions, ensuring history displays correctly when switching sources.</li>
          <li>[Fix] Resolved a critical bug where the fullscreen toggle was ignored; the launcher now correctly enforces your preferred window mode.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Significant performance boost for mod list scrolling, eliminating icon flickering via an improved pre-loading and buffering system.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Improved layout of deletion confirmation dialogs for better touch and gamepad interaction.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
      </release>

    <release version="0.1.33" date="2026-05-08">
      <description>
        <p xml:lang="zh_CN">集成 Authlib-injector 支持与披风自定义功能</p>
        <ul xml:lang="zh_CN">
          <li>[新功能] 集成 Authlib-injector 支持，支持第三方登录（如小皮肤、LittleSkin 等）。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 支持自定义披风 URL，让你的角色外观更加个性化。</li>
          <li>[新功能] 新增客户端安装遥测功能，并提供相关的隐私设置开关。</li>
          <li>[优化] 重构了身份验证服务与登录界面，显著提升系统稳定性。</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Integrated Authlib-injector Support and Custom Cape Support</p>
        <ul>
          <li>[New] Added Authlib-injector support for third-party authentication services like LittleSkin.</li>
          <li>[New] Added support for custom cape URLs.</li>
          <li>[New] Introduced client installation telemetry with a dedicated privacy toggle in settings.</li>
          <li>[Optimization] Restructured authentication services and overhauled the login UI for better stability.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>

  </releases>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <supports>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>pointing</control>
    <control>touch</control>
    <control>gamepad</control>
  </supports>

  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/MrShellad/pilauncher</url>
  <url type="homepage">https://pil.nav4ai.net</url>



</component>
